Emmanuel Obogbaimhe

email: eobogbai[at]buffalo[dot]edu c: (646)255-0160

Professional Summary

Interested in building mobile and interactive web applications as well as writing fully functioning software with the appropriate tools and technologies. Experienced in object-oriented programming. Also in developing, reading, debugging and testing code. Able to efficiently learn and master new technologies.

Work Experience

Developer @ Havilahgold. Valley Stream, NY

Update content on the site. Build UI functionalities (modals, sections, graphics, etc.). Fix minor bugs in the backend (PHP).

Software Engineer (Intern) @ Doolli. Buffalo, NY (June 2015 - August 2015)

Designed features for the UI. Fixed issues such as AJAX calls, widget issues, etc. Collaboration with a team of designers and senior developers.

Software Engineer (Intern) @ MITYO. Buffalo, NY (June 2015 - August 2015)

Designed database schema. Structure planning for the application.

CSTEP Research Internship. Buffalo, NY (August 2014 - December 2015)

Research intern, worked under the mentorship of Research Associate Professor Dr. Bina Ramamurthy. Assisted in the creation choreographiclineage.buffalo.edu (a web based genealogical network designed for artists such as dancers).

Habitat For Humanities. Buffalo, NY (July 2014)

Voluntary community service where I helped construct a house.

ICB Youth Summer Camp. Brooklyn, NY (July 2012)

Served as a leader in charge of supervising the children and teenagers during camp activities.

Technical Skills

Java | C/C++ | JavaScript | JQuery | NodeJs | ExpressJs | MongoDB | MySQL | HTML5 | CSS | PHP | WordPress | Angular | Git | Android

Projects

Stormer (June 2016)

Brain-Storming application that listens in on a conversation and simultaneously looks up ideas according to the topic of discussion. Reports the results in graphic and text form.

ColsNet.com (April 2016)

Redesigned the interface as well as fixed bugs on the site.

Rccgbrooklyn.org (April 2016 - Present)

Update content on the site Manage database and backend (PHP and MySQL)

KAP Android Mobile Application (March 2016 - Present)

Scripture based mobile application

Pulls up to date devotional readings from the server (NodeJs, Express for the backend and MongoDB as database)

Community Information Database/Website (March 2015)

Worked in a group where we created a database that stored information on the city of Buffalo (such as its major attractions, schools, shopping centers, etc.) which can be a useful tool for young professionals and tourists. Website: clairvoyance.us

Mobile Tracking Application (December 2014)

Assisted in the design of a mobile tracking device that allows the user to track how fast a vehicle is moving.

Chat Client (May 2014)

Created a simple easy to use instant messenger using Java. Users are able to login using their credentials. A user can send a chat request to another user with their username. The user receiving the request has the option to either block the request or allow the request. If the request is allowed then the connection is made and the users are now in a chat session. However if the request is rejected then no connection is made (using Java Socket library).

Data Aggregation and Validation for Digital Choreographic Lineage (June 2014)

Research project in which I worked under the mentorship of a Research Associate Professor in the Computer Science Department

Athletics Database Management (May 2013)

Worked in a team of three to create a website for the school's athletic teams.

Generated a database for the athletic teams which I organized based on the data collected (used MySQL).

Activities & Competitions

AngelHack Brooklyn. Brooklyn, NY (June 2016)

A two day on-going programming competition. Created a Brain Storming application that assists users in generating ideas.

Teach Kids to Code. Manhattan, NY (June 2016)

Served as a mentor where I taught kids to code with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Helped them build their own interactive web pages which they presented to an audience.

CSTEP Statewide Conference. Lake George, NY (April 2015)

One of five students selected from the University at Buffalo to present research at the Statewide Conference in Lake George, NY

M&T Bank Application Development Engineering Intramural. Buffalo, NY (February 2015)

Worked in a team of five to create a mobile application for M&T Bank.

UB Hackathon. Buffalo, NY (May 2014)

Three day programming competition held at the University at Buffalo.

Research Symposium. Buffalo, NY (July 2014)

Event where I presented my research to an audience which included judges. Placed in the top three, received an award for my research and a fully-paid trip to the Sagamore Resort Statewide Conference where I presented my research.

McNair Conference Niagara Falls. Niagara Falls, NY (July 2014)

Attended the McNair Conference where I presented my research to various audiences.

Co-Founder of FlashChaos.net (February 2005 - August 2006)

Created the website FlashChaos.net which was based on graphics, animations (cartoon series, games, etc.), and tutorials. Implemented an interactive forum for users to communicate with one another and share ideas.

Relevant Coursework

Data Structures | Algorithms | Machine Learning | Operating Systems | Communications | Database Organization

Education